[♪ opening theme song playing]
[wind howling]
[STARK] Looks like it keeps
going forever from up here.
I can't even see
all the way to the bottom.
[FRIEREN]
It's a 3,000-meter drop.
This is the deepest canyon
on the entire continent.
The climb may have felt slow,
but the elevation here
is immense.
You've been here before.
-So how do we cross it?
-[wind gushes]
[FERN] The wind is quite strong.
Flying magic is too risky.
[STARK] Again with the crossing.
Again with the wind.
[FRIEREN] If we head upstream,
we could cross at the river.
But we would
have to forge through
a treacherous mountain range.
A lengthy and dangerous detour.
We could go downstream,
couldn't we?
Only one problem seaside.
There's a cliff that's also
3,000 meters.
Apparently,
it's a sight to behold
if you'd like to drop by.
[FERN] No, thank you.
[FRIEREN]
Either way, at this rate,
it's going to take us
a bare minimum of two weeks
to safely cross the canyon.
My feet can't take it.
Not like we have
any other choice, right?
[FRIEREN] Hmm...
I imagine
it's in the final stages.
What's in the final stages?
For now,
let us continue upstream.
If we're lucky, we'll come upon
a nifty shortcut.
♪
Our shortcut.
[FRIEREN] I had a good feeling.
[STARK] There's a bridge?
You should've led with that.
[FRIEREN] At last,
looks like he's finished it.
[footsteps]
[FRIEREN] Gehen.
[GEHEN] It's been
a while, Frieren.
[FRIEREN] Seems your
bridge project was a success.
-[GEHEN] Indeed.
-[FERN] You know him?
[FRIEREN] This is Gehen,
the skilled dwarven carpenter
who spent the past two centuries
building this bridge.
[STARK] So dedicated.
I'm surprised
to see it finished.
A bridge this well-made
should be a major crossing,
yet I haven't heard it mentioned
or recorded on any maps.
I assumed that meant
it was still in progress.
And perhaps we would find you
in the last stretch.
[GEHEN] Frieren...
there is still one more problem
for me to solve.
[loud whooshing]
[wind gushes]
[GEHEN] Right on cue.
A flock of bird monsters
have been stirring up
powerful gusts of wind.
Some merchants came through
on their journey
to the so-called Golden Land.
They were blown over
the side, wagon and all.
You can slay them,
-but they'll only keep coming.
-[wings flapping]
They've built a nest
and made this canyon
their playground.
In doing so, they've rendered
my bridge useless.
Fortunately, the nest is located
on this side.
Could you help me
solve my problem?
I can't let 200 years
of work go to waste.
As for payment?
[GEHEN] A spell that lets you
flip pancakes perfectly.
I have all the ingredients.
A breakfast of dreams
is just one chore away.
-[Fern gasps]
-[STARK] Uh...
-You have a deal.
-[Fern grunts]
♪
[wind howling]
According to Gehen,
we should be drawing near.
[FERN] That path is
awfully close to the edge.
Watch where you step.
Your bodies would be
impossible to find.
♪
Why did Gehen
take it upon himself
to build a bridge here
in the first place?
I'm sure regret had
something to do with it.
[HIMMEL] I see.
So, it's still
under construction.
That's a shame.
Do you know
when it will be finished?
[GEHEN] I'm not sure
it will ever be.
I ran out of funds.
Doesn't that sting?
All the time in the world
and none of the money.
Tell us, Gehen,
why are you so determined
to build a bridge out here?
[GEHEN] In a happier time,
this is where my village sat.
Still would if it weren't
for the demons.
Unfortunately for us,
the closest army was stationed
in a city across the canyon.
This bridge
could've saved them,
but too little, too late.
Should've thought
to build it sooner.
[footsteps]
[HIMMEL]
Perhaps this can help.
Our reward
from a distant noble.
Demons stole a treasured sword
and my party helped reclaim it.
[GEHEN] This is a lot of money.
Thank you,
but I can't accept this.
I have nothing suitable
to offer you in exchange.
[HIMMEL] You have this bridge.
[GEHEN] Huh? You're a human.
By the time
I finish construction,
you'll have died of old age.
[Himmel chuckles softly]
[HIMMEL] Then Frieren
will accept your repayment.
[Frieren gasps softly]
Give her at least
a thousand years.
Build it to last.
[GEHEN] That I can do.
You can count on me.
♪
[FRIEREN] Here they are.
Let's begin.
[whooshing]
[Stark grunting]
♪
[FRIEREN] Gehen...
We took care of the monsters.
[GEHEN] Thank you, Frieren.
Now folks can freely
cross the canyon.
My work here is done.
What now?
Do you have any other
big projects ahead of you?
[GEHEN] Hmm...
I'm building my peace.
A quiet life in my village.
[MAN 1]
Hey, look who's back.
[MAN 2]
And just in time for dinner.
That's amazing news, Gehen.
This calls for celebration.
[GEHEN] Frieren...
Two hundred years
is more than enough time
for a village to be built anew.
Of course.
♪
[FRIEREN]
Well, shall we be off, then?
[Fern groaning]
Is something wrong?
[FRIEREN] We may or may not be
low on travel funds.
[STARK] Ah!
You didn't leave us with enough
to get through a single week.
[Frieren groans softly]
[sighs] Mistress, you can't
keep wasting all our money.
Not like it matters now.
What are we buying
in the middle of a snowfield?
Mm. Don't you worry.
I have just the solution.
[FRIEREN]
We're changing course.
Prepare your pockets.
What is this?
[STARK] Not a village,
that's for sure.
Maybe some adventurer camp?
[MAN] All right, boys,
let's get out there
and give it all we've got.
[ALL] Yeah!
Where have you taken us
this time?
[FRIEREN] Stark is correct that
it's a camp for adventurers.
Those seeking
holy snow crystals.
Am I supposed to know
what that is?
[FRIEREN]
It's a mineral
produced in the snowfields
of this region.
They're used to create
magic potions.
This is the only place
in the world
where they can be mined,
so they fetch a high price.
I get what we're doing.
Now ready your pickaxes, ladies,
because these holy snow crystals
aren't gonna mine themselves!
You've seen so much
yet remain so naive.
Holy snow crystals
aren't something you can
simply stumble upon.
That's why
they're so expensive.
Then how are we gonna
make any money here?
Have you ever been
to a marketplace
that caters exclusively
to adventurers?
You'll find it very interesting.
[STARK] It looks like your run
of the mill marketplace to me.
Now look closer.
A whole silver
for a loaf of bread?
That's more than ten times
the market price.
For their clientele is as rich
as they are hungry.
Mining is hard work,
but their bounties are worth
their weight in gold.
It only makes sense
prices are higher here.
Let's change careers.
There are two primary reasons
holy snow crystals sell
for such a high price.
The first of which
is their rarity.
The second reason
is that this region
is teeming with savage monsters.
Do you see
where I'm going with this?
Judging by what
they charge for bread,
monster slaying requests would
fetch a rather hefty reward.
Right as always, Fern.
-[fire crackling]
-[MAN] Up here.
There's a massive mineral vein
that only us locals know about.
I'd like you to defeat
the monster dwelling there.
One more thing.
Once you've slain the beast,
please set up
an anti-personnel barrier.
Anti-personnel?
Yes. I don't want
the wrong people
getting too close.
Understood. We'll take the job.
[FERN]
I'm grateful for the work,
but an anti-personnel barrier
feels like
a fairly unusual request.
It takes time to gather
the manpower
and funds required
for a mining operation.
If you wish to claim
a plot of land
but lack the resources to begin,
an anti-personnel barrier
is your best option.
[Fern sighs]
[FRIEREN] In any case,
we have a monster to slay.
♪
[FRIEREN] There it is.
That thing is giant.
Be sure to keep your guard up.
We were hired for this job
as a last resort.
If the adventurers at camp
could've taken care of this,
they would have.
Lack caution, and you'll die.
It's only fair that the risk
matches the reward.
Let's get to work.
[monster growls]
[roaring]
[Stark grunts]
[Stark gasps]
Mistress, it's reacting
to our mana.
What an annoying detail.
[Stark grunting]
[STARK]
It's faster than it looks.
[FRIEREN] Stark, run!
It's the first step of my plan.
That I can do!
[FERN] Higher.
[Stark pants, gasps]
[grunting, panting]
[gasps]
[Stark yells]
♪
[Stark pants, grunts]
[Stark yells]
[Stark sighs]
[STARK] They made us
work for that reward.
[both chuckle softly]
Mistress Frieren?
-[FRIEREN] Quiet.
-[Fern gasps]
[growling]
Great. From bad to worse.
It's safe to assume
our last opponent
was the lord of this area.
Nearby monsters must have
sensed its mana fading
and gathered here
to investigate.
Any more plans, Frieren?
I have the energy
to carry you two and run
if we wanna go that route.
Far too late for that.
[STARK] We're surrounded.
-[growling]
-Indeed, but even if we weren't,
we would still need
to slay them all
in order to complete the job.
Think you have
enough mana, Fern?
I should fare just fine.
[FRIEREN] We've no other choice.
[FRIEREN]
The Chivalric Order of Norm.
It was clear
they were moving somewhere,
so we followed them
to find out where and why.
We weren't expecting
to find you three.
Of course not,
though we appreciate the help.
We've done nothing
compared to you.
[FRIEREN] Mm?
Master Norm says
that we're in your debt.
That you have done much
to help our cause.
I suppose this makes us even.
[captain chuckles]
[CAPTAIN] Farewell.
[hoofbeats receding]
I can't believe they rode
all the way here. Impressive.
Agreed. That squad is charged
with watching over
their entire territory.
Even if it's little by little,
the Northern Plateau
is changing.
It's long past sunset, huh?
How about we set up
camp here tonight?
[fire crackling]
[Frieren groans softly]
Mistress Frieren,
time to wake up.
Come see this.
[Frieren groans softly]
[FRIEREN] Just five more hours.
[FERN] Fine,
-but you'll have to freeze.
-[groans]
-It's worth waking up for.
-[Frieren groans]
[FERN] The way the light
shimmers through the crystals...
The vein is beautiful
in the morning sun.
[Frieren gasps softly]
[FRIEREN] You're right.
♪
And to think
we only made a detour
to bolster our travel funds.
I wasn't expecting to come upon
such a feast for the eyes.
[EISEN] It's beautiful.
[HIMMEL] This is
more than enough reason
to see our quest
through to the end.
♪
[HIMMEL] If we defeat
the Demon King,
a time will come when anyone
can enjoy this beautiful sight.
Not just anyone could make
this harsh journey.
But in this era, more people
will see this wonder
than in any era before.
It's a strange feeling.
[FERN] It really is beautiful.
[STARK] Yeah.
Yet soon enough,
it will be broken into rubble
by human hands.
It's a bit sad,
but no one can stop
the march of time.
Take it in.
Once you have, we'll erect
the barrier and head back.
[MAN] A job well done.
Thank you.
Here's your reward.
I'm just relieved we can finally
preserve the vein.
Preserve?
So, you aren't intending
to mine it later?
It was in my childhood here
that I decided my fate.
One glimpse
of that beautiful sight
and I knew I wanted
to become an adventurer.
Now it's safe.
Thanks for protecting
the wonders of my home.
Of course.
♪
Protecting other people's homes
is an important job, huh?
Yes, it is.
The more I look back on it now,
the surer I am
that Master Heiter
protected my home, too.
It's true that war left
my physical home in ruins.
Even so, because of him,
I have the precious memories.
[Fern chuckles softly]
[Stark chuckles softly]
[STARK]
Those are what count.
When I told you the story
about me fleeing my home,
you didn't let it impact
your opinion of me
in the slightest.
You continued to believe in me.
Nothing's changed.
You always encourage me
and push me forward.
Why?
♪
[FERN] Because that's what
Mistress Frieren would do.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
-[Stark groans]
-[Fern sighs]
[FERN] Mistress Frieren,
you know the prices here
are astronomical,
yet you went shopping?
A magic item like this
is a rare find.
Just like that, we're back
to barely scraping by.
[Fern chuckles softly]
I had a feeling
this would happen,
so I hid our cut of the reward.
[STARK] Seriously?
You never let me down, Fern.
And that is why
you are my student.
[Fern chuckles softly]
[STARK] Always a mystery.
Well, shall we be off, then?
[LERNEN] This is Edel,
a second-class mage.
She specializes
in mental magic.
I asked her to accompany me
so she could reexamine the area.
She obtained some
new information.
Information you, for one,
will surely find valuable.
Denken, your hand...
I'll transfer the memories
to you.
[DENKEN] Go ahead.
[LERNEN] And with that,
I leave you to your work.
Your duty is straightforward.
Maintain and manage
the barriers surrounding
the golden land.
That is your charge.
You shall do nothing more
and nothing less.
♪
[EDEL] Denken...
Her grave is just a hole
in the ground.
[DENKEN] I'm aware.
[EDEL] He intends to die.
Yet I feel a touch of envy,
for never in my wildest dreams
would I defy Mistress Serie.
[LERNEN] The final
and the strongest
of the Seven Sages awaits him.
Macht of the Golden Land.
The valiant Denken
shall fight to the bitter end
to save his gleaming home.
Fate pulls him like
he's the hero in a fairy tale.